字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
最新最快海外影视字幕下载
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
ZiMuZu
倾情奉献
翻译
草草
木浅
翻译
磁芯章鱼X
showeryhe
翻译
小酸奶!
累
翻译
冬麟
时间轴
宝宝  念念
电脑狂人
第三季
第八集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
顾问
somehacker
1986年12月19日
四个月前
1986年10月31日
留言板
你安全吗
各位  我要弄清楚  乔·麦克米伦  是英雄还是骗子
1986年12月18日
穆特尼
无数据
你并不安全
留言板
你安全吗
你并不安全
麦克米伦先生
Mr. MacMillan.
我们需要问你几个问题
We need to ask you a few questions.
都打包  贴好标签
...pack 'em up and label it.
你还有别的电脑吗
Do you have any additional computers?
你是说我还买了别的电脑吗  没有
You mean, do I own another computer? No.
我能不能用别的电脑  当然  你也能
Do I have access to other computers? Sure, so do you.
你可以去图书馆
You can go to your library,
可以去你朋友家
you can go to your friend's house--
把你所有曾使用过的
Write down all the locations
电脑的地址写下来
of computers you have access to.
别费劲了  里面什么都没有
Have at it. There's nothing there.
嗯  他们来查我的时候我也这么说的
Yeah, that's what I said when they came for me, too.
这是什么东西
What the hell is that?
小子  没见过数据包嗅探器吗
Oh, kid, you've never seen a packet sniffer?
这就是你最大的敌人
Meet your worst enemy.
你要去哪
Where you going?
我只是
I'm just, um--
我去买些吃的
I'm just gonna go grab a bite to eat.
他们让你别出门
They told you not to leave.
他们接到电话线接口上的玩意到底是什么
What was that thing that they were shoving into the phone jack?
你什么都没做  对吧
You-- you didn't do anything, right?
万一他们回来我怎么说
Hey, what should I tell them if they come back?
什么都别说
Just don't say anything.
再见
Good morning.
刚那群人是谁啊
What the hell was that?
联调局的
The FBI.
该死的  乔
God damn it, Joe.
他们在找莱恩
They're looking for Ryan.
他  做了件傻事
He, uh-- he did a stupid thing.
他把麦克米伦实用网络的
He-- he released the source code
杀毒软件的源代码发布到网上去了
for MacMillan Utility's anti-virus software online.
-你在逗我吗  -全都发布了
- You've got to be kidding. - All of it.
违反了《计算机欺诈和滥用法案》
It's a violation of the CFAA--
他们以为是你做的
They think you did it.
我知道你要说什么
I know what you're gonna say.
大家都会说一样的话  乔
It's what everyone's gonna say, Joe.
-请你听我说  -别  别说了
- Please, listen. - Stop, stop!
别说了
Stop.
看着我的眼睛
Look me in the eye
告诉我你和代码泄露一点关系都没有
and tell me you had nothing to do with the leak.
我完全不知情
I had nothing to do with it.
那好  那我支持你
All right. Then I'm all in.
我们一起想办法
All right? We'll figure this out together.
穆特尼增长的步伐近来确实略显放慢
While it's true that the pace of Mutiny's growth has slowed somewhat,
但向多平台扩展并不是唯一的出路
multi-platform expansion is not the only solution.
正相反  穆特尼正在实施多项战略
Rather, Mutiny is employing a number of strategies
多管齐下  将使我公司二季度收入大幅上涨
which, taken together, promise a second quarter earnings uptick--
停  你不能这么说
Stop. You can't say that.
招股书里没有提这些
It's not in the prospectus.
那我总得说点什么吧
Well, I have to say something.
他们能看到用户数量不再增长了
They can see that that user numbers are plateauing.
公司可喜的增长
The company's laudable record of growth
在招股书里都详细记录了
is fully documented in the prospectus.
这听起来好像我在隐瞒什么
That sounds like I'm hiding something.
股票怎么宣传都不为过
You can't hype the stock.
如果我只能念招股书
Well, what's the point of doing this road show
那这样到处奔走还有什么意义
if all I can say is read the prospectus?
为了让他们看招股书
So, they read the prospectus.
我有一些想要说明的内容
Well, there are things that I want to clarify.
招股书应该是一个动态文件
The prospectus should be a living document.
-它不是  -抱歉  证监会有规定
- Well, it's not. - Sorry, SEC rules.
你做得很好了
Look, you're doing great.
我们先见这些小公司的意义就在于
The whole point of coming to these smaller firms first
让你能调整好
is so that you can work out the kinks
再拿去给波士顿和纽约的大公司看
before we take it to the big guns in Boston and New York.
昨晚不是挺顺利的吗
I thought it went pretty well last night, don't you think?
不  我觉得他们不怎么感兴趣
No, I think they were all underwhelmed.
我的感觉就是如此
Hey, I read the room as I see it.
你做得挺好的
You did fine.
幸运的是  丹佛对于科技的投资不多
Fortunately, there isn't much investment capital for tech in Denver.
大家都讨厌这个步骤
Look, everybody hates this process,
但也都能撑过去
and everybody gets through it.
继续吧  讲讲穆特尼创始人卡梅伦·豪伊
So, come on, tell me about Mutiny's founder Cameron Howe.
我知道她已经离开了公司
I understand she's no longer with the company.
卡梅伦是硅谷最有天分的程序员之一
Cameron is one of the most talented coders in Silicon Valley.
她将心血都投给了穆特尼
She gave her heart and soul to Mutiny,
-她的精神依然...  -拜托
- and her spirit is still very much-- - Oh, please!
简直像在给宠物狗念悼词
It sounds like you're eulogizing the family dog.
我们说好这样说的
That's what we agreed I'd say.
听上去不像回事
It doesn't pass the smell test.
那你有更好的主意吗
Do you have a better suggestion?
比如加一点点真实的成分进去
Something with a faint hint of truth to it, maybe?
所以我应该说她是喜怒无常的自恋狂
Oh, so I should say that she's a temperamental narcissist
具有自我毁灭倾向  完全无法合作吗
with self-destructive tendencies who doesn't work with others?
至少你说这话时听起来很可信
Well, at least it sounds like you mean it when you say that.
我很抱歉这话没法说得更好听
I'm sorry that there's no pretty way to talk about this.
但我提醒你  你也投票同意了的
But just a reminder, you voted for it, too.
是同意了  但我记得好像是被迫的吧
Yes, I did, under duress, as I recall.
没人希望如此  事情已经如此了
Nobody wanted it. It's just what happened.
但现在我们还得面对
And yet, here we are.
我只是想帮忙
Look, I'm just trying to help out here.
要不然我出去端咖啡
Unless you just want me to go get the coffee?
你这就要走了
Are you leaving already?
嗯  我觉得我还是等第二周
Yeah, I figured I'd wait till my second week
再开始迟到吧
till I start showing up late.
你能去一下商店吗
Hey, can you, uh, run to the store,
备点糖给来要的小孩
get some candy for the trick or treaters?
卡梅  那些小孩想要糖果
Cam, they're kids, they want candy,
而你该尽量出门走走
and you should try to get out a little bit.
-你能代劳吗  -不行
- Can you do it? - Mmm, no.
-我爱你  -爱你
- I love you. - Love you.
那边是优胜场
...Winner's Circle over here.
大钱都在那儿赢
That's where you go to win most of the money,
虽然你坐自己位置上
though you can win some bonus money
也可以赚点小奖
at your chairs over there--
中个一万到两万五美金
10 and $25,000 to crack over there.
这些是今天第一局的主题
These are the subjects in the first game today.
有"水  到处是水"
We've got "Water, Water Everywhere";
"不停来回"  "回想那时"
"Round And Round"; "Remember When";
"将之封存"  "很快归来"
"Keep Them Sealed"; "We'll Be Right Back"--
听着像广告似的
sounds like commercial messages.
我也不懂那是什么  但听着真像广告
I don't know what that is, but that sure sounds like what it is.
"金刚之子"  还有...
"King Kong's Kid"; and we have...
我是莱恩·雷
It's Ryan Ray.
乔和戈登的交易
This deal between Joe and Gordon,
就是扯淡
it's bullshit.
我才是元老
I was there from the beginning.
没有我那个网络根本不会存在
The network wouldn't exist without me.
我比戈登·克拉克强二十倍
And I'm better than Gordon Clark by a magnitude of 20.
戈登想在TCP/IP更新上向思科妥协
Gordon wants to roll over for Cisco on TCP/IP upgrades.
传输控制／网际协议
他就是个笑话  毫无远见
It's so short-sighted, he's a joke!
这就是你们的合作伙伴
That's who you're in business with.
我不知道该说什么  米奇
I don't know what to say, Mitch.
抱歉你要这样得知
I'm sorry you had to find out this way.
我投入太多  无法一走了之
I was too invested in this project to just walk away.
听我说  乔  我们喜欢你
Listen, Joe, we like you.
你相信这个网络大有可为
You believed in the network.
你们董事会投票反对我们
Hell, you walked away from your own company
你就离开了自己的公司
when your board voted against us.
可是莱恩  咱们直说吧
But Ryan-- let's face it,
莱恩这家伙可不像会乖乖闭嘴的人
Ryan doesn't sound like a guy who's gonna keep his mouth shut.
可能下一个就打给我老板
His next call could be to my boss.
莱恩绝不会那么做
Ryan would never do that.
不管怎么说  这家伙
Well, regardless, we can't work with someone
现正接受计算机诈骗调查
who's being investigated for computer fraud,
公然触犯了今年生效的重要法案
who blatantly violated major legislation
我们不能跟他合作
that went into effect this year.
乔没做错什么
Joe didn't do anything wrong.
我没说他错了
I'm not saying he did.
但除非我们找到责任人
But until we find the person who is responsible,
你们俩该保持距离
you two need to stay away from each other.
这项网络合同先暂缓
And this network contract is frozen.
莱恩怎么知道我们在合作
How did Ryan know that we were working together?
连我和思科谈判的细节都清楚
Down to the details of my negotiations with Cisco?
他肯定看了我们的电子邮件
He must be reading our emails.
网络是他搭的  他比谁都清楚如何进去
He built the network. He knows how to get inside better than anyone.
我们得告发他
We gotta turn him in.
不行  肯定有别的办法
No, there must be another way.
你在说什么  你没听见那录音吗
What are you talking about? Did you hear the tape?
-合同被暂缓了  -我不能那样对他
- The contract's frozen. - I can't do that to him.
老天爷啊  乔
Oh, Christ, Joe.
他是我朋友
He's my friend.
我以为我是你朋友
I thought I was your friend.
不是吗
No?
好了  天啊  这就来
All right. Jesus, I'm coming.
不给糖就捣乱
Trick or treat!
好几个小时了只有你没扮成公主
You're the first non-princess I've seen for hours.
我讨厌公主
I hate princesses.
我也是
Me, too.
你只有一种糖
You only got one thing.
是啊  不拿就走吧
Yeah. Take it or leave it.
阿福
Alf.
赶快
Shoo.
看啊
Well...
一个高个儿孩子扮成了乔·麦克米伦
it's a very tall child dressed as Joe MacMillan.
蝙蝠侠卖光了
Batman was sold out.
我能进去吗
Can I come in?
当然
Yeah.
颜色不错
It's a good color.
还没刷完呢
It's a work in progress.
你找我什么事
So, what's going on?
我想你来不是为了要糖果吧
I assume you're not here for the candy?
我遇到麻烦了
I've got a problem.
你是遇到很多麻烦了吧
It sounds like you got a lot of problems.
除非是真的  不然就没有所谓负面报道
I mean, unless it's true there's no such thing as bad publicity.
我...
I'm--
源代码泄露不是我做的
I'm not responsible for the leak.
我想到了
I, yeah, figured.
显然是有真本事的人干的
You know, clearly it was someone with actual skills.
我是说  很明显是莱恩干的
I just mean obviously it was Ryan.
我得找到他  可他失踪了
I need to find him and he's off the grid.
联调局每周都给我打电话
The feds are calling me every week.
肯定的  可能是因为每个线上聊天室
I bet, probably because every chat room online
都认为你是个8位的罗宾汉
thinks you're some kind of 8-bit Robin Hood.
我没强迫莱恩这么做
I didn't make Ryan do this.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
很难强迫莱恩做任何事
It's hard to make Ryan do anything.
你能不能发个信号什么的
If you could send out a kind of flare--
莱恩很有才  但要是有人能追踪到他
I mean, Ryan's talented, but if anyone can track him...
你要把他交给警察吗
Are you gonna turn him in?
不  我是担心他
No, I'm worried about him.
他要走投无路了
He's running out of options.
抱歉
Sorry.
你怎么样
How are you doing?
好得不得了
Never better,
你肯定看得出来
as I'm sure you can see.
看看我们
Well, look at us.
两名被自己公司
Two unemployed CEOs
赶出来的执行总裁
both ousted from our companies.
我的公司死定了  而你的要上市了
Mine's toast and yours is going public.
戈登和我说了
Gordon told me.
好吧
Yeah.
我现在和戈登合作了
I'm working with Gordon now.
真的吗
Really?
真是意外
Now, there's a twist.
你说得对
You were right.
我应该承认他
I needed to give him credit
带上他
and include him,
我对我们共同研发的东西很期待
and we're working on something that I'm really excited about.
所以  谢谢你
So, uh, thank you for that.
好吧
Yeah, well...
谢谢你
thank you.
他啊
Him.
你选的人不错
Well, you picked a good guy.
他很幸运
He's lucky.
不  我觉得我现在只让他觉得痛苦
No, I'm pretty sure right now I'm just making him miserable.
我长大以后就再没见过这玩意了
Oh, I haven't seen one of these since I was a kid.
真吓人
That's scary.
是啊
Yeah.
因为万圣节  我不得不把它捅了
I had to zap it 'cause of Halloween.
不想让那些小鬼被叮
I didn't want those little wieners getting stung.
如果你帮我找到莱恩  我会很感激
I'd appreciate your help with Ryan.
乔
Hey, Joe.
拿着  不给糖就捣蛋
Here. Trick or treat.
克拉克家
Clark residence.
亲爱的  服装准备得怎么样了
Hi, sweetheart. How's your costume?
挺好的  有点痒
Good. A little itchy.
我的老师说应该把我的矛叫做拐杖
And my teacher said I have to call my spear a walking stick.
为什么
Why?
我不知道  小孩子不该拿矛吗
I don't know. Kids aren't supposed to have spears?
能有想象的矛吗
Well, can they have imaginary spears?
我不知道  我没问
I don't know. I didn't ask that.
那你告诉她
Well, you tell her--
爸爸  妈妈的电话
Daddy, Mommy's on the phone!
海莉  好好玩  亲爱的
Haley? Have the best time, okay, sweetheart?
-怎么样了  -挺好的
- How's it going? - Pretty good.
我觉得我今天表现不错  你那边怎么样
I think I did all right today. How are things over there?
很好  一切都很好
Great. Everything's great.
-不  辫子  -是琼妮吗  我能和她说话吗
- No, a braid. - Is that Joanie? Can I talk to her?
妈妈想和你说话
Hey, Mom wants to talk to you.
编头发的时候不行  会偏的
Not while you're braiding. It'll be all lopsided.
-好吧  -没关系
- All right. - That's okay.
让她玩得开心点  好吗
Just tell her to have fun, all right?
她要扮成谁
What's she going as?
琼·蒙大纳
Joan Montana.
记得拍照  好吗
Take pictures, okay?
好的
Will do.
戈登  我好想你
Gordon, I-- I miss you.
我也想你
Yep, miss you, too.
快点  爸爸
Hurry up, Daddy.
两个孩子  一场大戏
Two kids, three-ring circus.
海莉就像个小检察官
Haley's like a tiny prosecutor.
她一直跑来给我们看她姐姐捣乱的证据
She kept coming down here to offer evidence against her sister.
琼妮太吓人  我不敢定她罪
Yeah, Joanie's too scary to convict.
青少年的她渐渐要冒头了
Her teenage self is lurking on the horizon
就像后天启时代的破坏者
like some post-apocalyptic ravager.
破坏者
Ravager, huh?
你根本无法想象
You have no idea.
你有些消息了吧
So, um, I was hoping you had heard some news.
他没来消息
I haven't heard from him.
我能问你件事吗
Can I ask you a question?
你...
Were--
你和莱恩
were you and Ryan, um,
有过...你懂的
ever, uh... you know.
什么
What?
你...
Um, did you...
就那个
you know...?
懂吗
You know?
什么
What?
你懂的  你...
You know, were--
你们...
were you, you know,
不止是朋友吧
more than... friends?
明白吧
You know?
我对莱恩没有那种感觉
I never had those feelings for Ryan.
其实吧
Actually,
他让我想起你
he kind of reminds me of you.
拜托  请别这么说
Oh, come on, please don't say that.
我不知道该怎么回了
That's-- I don't know how to respond to that.
别整我了
Stop messing with me.
你应该独自继续国家科学基金网的项目
You should move forward with the NSFNET project alone.
什么  你什么意思
Wh-what? What are you talking about?
我不想拖你后腿
I don't want to hold you back.
你没拖我后腿  你在帮我
You're not holding me back. You're helping me.
戈登  米奇说得很清楚
Gordon, Mitch was pretty clear about this.
-乔  请别这样  -你也知道这种事
- Joe, please don't do this. - You know how these things work.
-如果你错过机会  -我一个人干不来
- If you miss the window-- - I can't do it alone.
你可以  不要妄自菲薄
Yes, you can. Don't sell yourself short.
我病了  乔
I'm sick, Joe.
-我病了  -什么意思
- I'm sick. - What-- what the hell does that mean?
我马上回来
Hang on real quick.
-戈登  -等等  我得接一下
- Gordon? - Hang on, I gotta get this.
-别管了  -可能是唐娜
- Leave it. - Look, it could be Donna.
给我两秒钟
Just give me two secs.
喂
Hello?
现在  不  我得照顾孩子  我...
Now? No, I got the kids. I--
好吧  我会想办法的
All right, look, I'll-- I'll figure something out.
好
Yep.
是穆特尼  他们要我...算了
That was Mutiny. They need me to-- it doesn't--
我们得谈谈
we need to talk, all right?
但现在我需要你帮我个忙
But right now I need a favor from you.
除非你告诉我怎么回事  否则哪也别想去
You're not going anywhere until you tell me what's going on.
-不行  我得去...  -坐下
- Look, I can't. I gotta go-- - Sit down.
坐
Sit.
莱恩
Ryan.
莱恩  莱恩
Ryan. Ryan!
你怎么找到我的
How'd you find me?
我在穆特尼建了"你安全吗"版块
I put up the "Are You Safe" board on Mutiny.
你通过FTP链接远程登录
You logged in remotely through an FTP connection--
你写了个软件陷阱
You wrote a software trap
向你报告我的活动  包括大学主线
alerting you to my activity, including the university mainlines.
我早该想到的
I should have thought about that.
我不是来抓你什么的
Hey, I'm not here to bust you or anything.
乔想帮你
Joe wants to help you.
我想帮你
I-- I want to help you.
你
Hey, you--
莱安  你不可能靠胡椒博士和奶酪饼干过一辈子
Ryan, you can't live off Dr Pepper and Cheez-Its forever.
相信我  我试过的
Believe me, I've tried.
你都去哪了
Where have you been?
我在朋友家借宿了一段时间
I crashed with friends for a while.
警察一直在找我
The cops, they keep tracking me.
你怎么知道
Uh, how did you know?
我能感觉到
I could feel it.
有人跟踪了我
Somebody was following me.
我的朋友
And-- and my buddy,
经常接到奇怪的来电
he kept getting these weird phone calls.
是吗
Yeah.
后来
And, um,
我搭大巴去了圣地亚哥
I took the bus down to San Diego
住在了亲戚家
and, um, stayed with my cousin.
他很崇拜搞技术的  也是个混蛋
He's a wannabe tech guy and a total asshole.
他说他不会把我供出去  但是我...
He said he wouldn't rat me out, but I--
我知道他会的
I knew he would, you know?
我搭车回到了旧金山
I hitched a ride back to SF.
我需要一杯咖啡和一台电脑  所以
I needed a cup of coffee and a computer, so...
我就混了进来
I blended in right here.
就像隐形人一样
It's like I'm invisible.
乔现在可能恨死我了
Joe probably hates me now.
不
Oh, no.
不  即使他真生气
No, and even if he is pissed,
也会原谅你的
he'll get over it.
乔有时候...
Joe can be...
会惊人的宽容
surprisingly forgiving.
也许是因为他已经毁了太多次自己的生活
Maybe it's because he's screwed up his own life so many times.
如果你不希望我告诉他你在哪  我不会说的
Hey, if you don't want me to tell him where you are, I won't.
但他真的就是想帮你考虑下出路
But he really just wants to walk you through your options.
他很担心你
He's worried about you.
你看
And look,
我找到你了
I found you,
所以...你躲不了一世
so... you can't hide forever.
我还以为你会把丫头们带来呢
I thought you were gonna bring the girlies along.
不
No.
找到个很棒的新保姆
Found a great new sitter.
特别好说话
Really flexible.
谢谢你帮忙
Well, thanks for bailing me out.
我不希望唐娜在这节骨眼上还要担心别的事
I didn't want to worry Donna on the eve of her big day.
好吧
Yeah.
你要拿你公开募股的股份怎么办
What you gonna do with your share of the IPO?
我不知道
I don't know.
我觉得我应该做点打算
I guess I should make some plans.
他们说会是15美元起价
You know, they're saying it's gonna open at 15.
15美元
15.
谁能想到
Who'd have thunk it?
你打算拿你的股份怎么办
What are you gonna do with your share?
一部分给我的孙子做
Stash away some for a college fund type of thing
大学基金之类的
for my grandson.
如果詹姆斯同意的话
That is, if that's all right with James.
是吗  他为什么会不同意
Yeah? Why wouldn't it be?
谁知道什么会惹到他呢
You never know what might hit a nerve.
好吧
All right.
你和卡梅聊过了吗
You talk to Cam?
没有
No.
你呢
You?
没有
Nope.
但是
But...
她明天就是百万富翁了
she'll be a millionaire tomorrow.
她肯定不会为此难过的
She can't be too sorry about that.
-敬上市  -敬上市
- Hey, here's to going public. - To going public.
当然了  谢谢
Yeah, you bet. Thanks so much.
不客气
No problem.
看看你
Well, look at you.
在前门等我
Waiting for me at the front door.
我们离终生梦想只差一条围裙了
We're one apron away from a lifelong fantasy.
我有个提议
I have a proposition for you.
我能先给你看点东西吗
Can I show you something first?
-好的  -好
- Yeah. - Okay, good.
-好  -好
- Okay. - Okay.
这叫《太空摩托编年史》
It's called the "Spacebike Chronicles."
-好  -这是主人公
- Okay. - This is our hero.
她还没有名字
She doesn't have a name.
她在天启后的未来里畅游
And she's just cruising through the post-apocalyptic future
骑着她酷炫的太空摩托
on her bad-ass space-bike.
她只需要汽油  糖果
And all she needs survive are gas, candy,
和偶尔洗个热水澡就能生存
and the occasional long, hot shower.
她前往行星  小行星  太空站
So, she travels to planets and asteroids and space stations
搜集她需要的东西
trying to get what she needs.
当她来到新的地方
And when she arrives at a new place,
她会去努力赢得五感之一
she tries to win one of the five senses.
每一感都能给她新的能力
Each one arms her with a different power.
分寸感让她可以改变大小
A sense of proportion allows her to change size.
幽默感让她可以抵御大部分袭击
A sense of humor allows her to fend off most forms of attack.
自我感让她可以显现消失
A sense of self allows her to appear and disappear.
正派并不能给她能力
Okay, well, decency doesn't give her an actual power,
但让她可以
but it makes it possible
赢得最罕见的一感
for her to win the rarest sense of all--
常识
common sense,
这能让她更清楚地看透一切
which lets her see everything more clearly.
太美妙了
It's beautiful.
怎么赢
How do you win?
不会赢  你可以一直玩下去
You don't, you just get to keep playing.
我喜欢
I love it.
来  过来
Come here. Come here, come up.
你想听一个提议吗
Do you want to hear, uh, the proposition?
你想搬去日本吗
How do you feel about moving to Japan?
什么
What?
他们要给我升职
They want to move me up.
派去东京
All the way to Tokyo.
太棒了
That's perfect.
-真的吗  -嗯
- Really? - Yeah.
莱恩
Ryan?
你为什么对我撒谎
Why'd you lie to me?
你为什么把我踢出去
Why'd you cut me out?
我没那么做
I didn't do either of those things.
-我是打算带上你的  -带上我
- I planned to bring you in. - Bring me in?
是我创造了它
I created the whole thing.
是我放出了代码
I put the code out there,
让它真正免费了
really made it free
而你没有胆这么做
when you didn't have the guts to do it yourself.
此后我一直在外面  维护你的名声
And I've been out there ever since, defending your name,
讲出真相
telling the real story.
我一直很担心你
I've been worried about you.
来坐下
Hey, sit down.
我知道你生气了  承认吧
I know you're angry, just admit it.
我没有
I'm not.
我确实希望你没有搅黄国家科学基金网的交易
I wish you hadn't upset the NSFNET deal.
你的确让事情难办多了
You've made things much harder.
但这远不如
But that is less important
你没事要紧
than knowing that you're okay.
在我看来
As I see it,
你有两个选择
you've got two options.
你可以自首  承认你做了什么
You can turn yourself in and own up to what you did...
或者你可以逃
or you can run.
不管怎样
Either way,
我都会帮你
I will help you.
怎么帮
How?
如果你逃
If you run,
我会给你五万块  送你去大巴站
I'll give you 50 grand, drive you to the bus station
你可以就此消失
and you can disappear.
但我们创立的网络
But the network you and I created
也会消失
will disappear, too.
不  我不希望那样
No, I don't want that.
我找过我的律师
I put in a call to my lawyer.
如果你自首
If you turn yourself in,
至多也就蹲一两年
you'll serve no more than a year or two.
不  我做不到
No, I can't.
听我说
Listen to me.
触犯《计算机欺诈和滥用法》的黑客
A hacker that violates the CFAA
至少五年不能碰电脑
can't touch a computer for at least five years--
五年  那简直疯了
Five years? That's insane!
这根本不是个选择
And that's an impossible choice!
总比蹲10年监狱强
It's better than 10 years in prison.
那是最高刑罚
That's the maximum.
我知道听上去好像很久
I know it sounds like a long time,
但你还年轻  就像你对我说的
but you're young, and it's like you told me,
毁灭带来改变
destruction leads to transformation.
你还有大把时间重塑自己
You've got plenty of time to reinvent yourself.
是啊  我就想这么办
Yeah, that's what I want to do.
跟你一起重新开始  就像你当初雇我时那样
Start again with you, like when you first hired me.
我们在这里开工  创造东西
We sat right here making shit up,
在白板上写下点子
writing ideas on the board.
好吧  好
Okay, all right.
好吧
Fine.
如果我
Let's say I--
我照你说的做
I do what you say
我服刑
and I serve my time.
我们还能一起工作吗
Tell me we can still work together.
那不可能
That's not possible.
但换你也会这么做的
But you would have done the same thing.
你就是干这种事的大师
You're a master at this kind of move.
乔·麦克米伦的典型作风
It's classic Joe MacMillan.
我不能再跟乔·麦克米伦一起工作了
I can't work with Joe MacMillan anymore.
好吧
Fine.
不管你帮不帮  我都要这么做
I'll do this with or without you.
我希望你成功
I hope you do.
你是个伪君子  一直都是
You're a hypocrite and you always have been.
你不用今晚决定
You don't have to decide tonight.
我希望你睡这儿
I want you to sleep here
我们可以早上再谈
and we can talk more in the morning.
你需要休息  莱恩
But you need some rest, Ryan.
我去拿床单  把沙发布置一下
I'll get some sheets and we can make up the sofa.
女士要我放在哪
Where would madam like the tray?
摆在床上吧
Oh, uh, on the bed, please.
还需要别的吗
Will there be anything else?
不了  谢谢
No, thank you.
唐娜
Donna?
你睡得如何
How'd you sleep?
不好  但我不在意
Oh, horribly, but I didn't really mind.
床单太舒服了
The sheets were so comfortable.
你吃过早餐了吗
Have you eaten breakfast?
不不  我紧张时不吃早餐
Oh, no, no. I don't do breakfast when I'm nervous.
我吃
I do.
我要上电视
I'm gonna be on TV
然后我的公司就要上市了
and then my company's going public.
你会表现很好的
You're gonna be great.
你总那么说
You always say that.
你就是很棒
No, you are.
你会很棒的
You're gonna be great.
好像对面是个人一样直视它
So, just look directly into it like it's a person.
琳达能看到你
Lynda will be able to see you.
她的声音会从耳机中传过来
Her voice will come into your earpiece.
会稍有声音延迟
There will be a bit of a sound delay.
有问题吗
Any questions?
还有五分钟
Five away.
好了  走吧
All right, come on, guys.
我想回床上去
I wanna go back to bed.
我知道  但我们得起来看妈妈
I know, but we gotta get up and watch Mommy.
好吗  今天是她的大日子
All right? It's her big day.
我待会儿就给你们
I'll make you guys some breakfast
做早餐  好吗
in just a little bit, okay?
好了  你们去沙发上吧
All right, you guys get on the couch.
来  起来
Come on, hop up.
给爸爸腾点地方
Gotta make some room for Daddy.
欢迎继续收看《财经早间报道》
Welcome back to "Financial Watch AM."
今早我们请来了唐娜·克拉克
This morning we have with us Donna Clark,
穆特尼执行总裁
CEO of Mutiny,
网上购物这个勇敢新世界的开拓者
a trailblazer in the brave new world of online shopping.
-欢迎  唐娜  -看  是妈妈
- Welcome, Donna. - Look, it's Mommy.
正是由于我们本期嘉宾这样的人
Thanks to people like our guest,
2.5千万拥有
for the 25 million Americans
私人电脑的美国人
who own personal computers,
可以靠键盘完成圣诞节购物
Christmas shopping is just a keystroke away.
-唐娜  -她看上去好美
- So, Donna... - She looks so pretty.
作为创建了科技公司的女人
a woman who founded a tech company.
你很不寻常  是吧
You're something of an anomaly, aren't you?
其实  穆特尼是由我的前合伙人
Well, actually, Mutiny was founded by my former partner,
卡梅伦·豪伊创立
Cameron Howe.
这样啊  他在哪呢
Ah, I see. And where is he?
是她  已经退出公司了
Uh, she is no longer with the company.
那么公司的确是由女人创建的
So, it was founded by a woman?
是的
Yes.
跟我们讲讲
So, how does it work,
这新电子零售的现象吧
this new e-tail phenomenon?
其实非常简单
It's very simple, really.
大部分家用电脑都是与调制解调器相连的
Most home computers are connected to something called a modem.
这个装置是...
That's a device which uses--
天呐  这听上去很复杂
Oh, dear, it's sounding complicated.
并不的
It isn't, really--
总之  我能用它买鞋吗
Bottom line-- can I buy my shoes with it?
当然了
Yes, absolutely.
我们在与多个零售商合作
We're in partnership with several retailers and--
终于有一件让人激动的电脑新闻了
Finally, something about computers to get excited about.
我究竟要怎么买鞋
So, how exactly would I buy my shoes?
登录穆特尼  在家...
Well, you would log on to Mutiny and from the home--
我们拦截了电话线的股票行情自动收录器信号
We intercepted the ticker feed from phone lines.
去往一间银行的
Going into a bank.
然后改道接入了办公室调制解调器
And then rerouted to the office modem.
-嗯  -听上去完全不合法嘛
- Yeah. - Well, that sounds entirely legal.
是啊
Sure.
好了  我声明  我对此计划并不知情
Okay, for the record I had no prior knowledge of this plan.
该死
Shit.
拜托  太没经验了
Oh, come on. Rookie move, son.
这是什么  帆船
What are you doing? Sailboat?
没挣到钱先别急着花啊
Don't spend your money before you've made it.
真白痴
What a dweeb!
好了  今天上市的公司会先出来
Okay, look. So, the companies debuting today come out first.
有多少
How many are there?
我不知道
I don't know.
-来了  来了  -看啊
- Oh, here we go. Here we go. - Hey, look at that.
钱  钱  钱
Money, money, money.
开始了
Okay, here we go.
好吧  比我们预期的低了一点
Okay, it's a little lower than we expected.
别紧张
Just breathe.
我们能给妈妈打电话了吗
Can we call Mommy yet?
我们恐怕得等等了
Uh, I think we're gonna wait a little.
你想知道吗
Do you wanna know?
告诉我是好是坏
Just... tell me if it's good or bad.
我知道这是个打击
I know it's a morale blow.
我知道
I get it.
但这不代表股票没有价值
But it doesn't mean that the stock is worthless.
只是不如我们想的值钱
It's just not worth what we thought.
可能是因为我们增长的速度
It could be the pace of our growth.
可能是因为受限于康懋达
It could be a Commodore issue.
他们这一季的销量很差
They had a horrible quarter.
或是时间问题  因素有很多...
Or just a calendar thing. There are all sorts of schools of--
能让我单独待会儿吗
Can I, um-- can I have a minute?
麦克米伦先生  我们得进去
Mr. MacMillan, we need to come in.
什么事
What's this about?
莱恩·雷昨晚在你公寓吗
Was Ryan Ray in your apartment last night?
是的
Yeah.
但他已经走了
But he's gone now.
我不知道他在哪
I don't know where he is.
先生  你坐下吧
Sir, why don't you sit down?
乔
Look, Joe,
你还要读多少遍啊
how many times are you going to read that?
他就是在这儿写的
He wrote it right here
趁我睡觉的时候
while I was sleeping.
我不能拿它挣钱
I can't profit from this.
不行
No.
不  这是你的点子
No, it was your idea.
好吗  我会等你的
Okay? I'll-- I'll wait for you.
我会想办法拖拖
You know? I'll see if I can stall things.
你不该想跟我共事
Yeah, you shouldn't want to work with me.
那晚上我
The night I was--
跟莱恩站在外面
stood out there with Ryan,
我们还说...
we talked about...
天呐  我不知道我都说了什么
God, I don't know what I was saying.
那不是
Look, that's--
他那么做的原因
that's not why.
老天啊
Jesus Christ.
我是想帮他
I was trying to help him.
你要怎么办
What are you gonna do?
我不知道
I don't know.
我不能总这样
I can't keep having this conversation.
我不干了
I'm done.
戈登
Hey, Gordon.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你真的不想推迟吗
Are you sure you don't want to postpone?
不知道会不会举办葬礼
I don't know if there's a funeral.
不  我们走吧
No, let's go.
真的吗  我们可以改航班的
Are you sure? 'Cause we can change our flight.
汤姆  我没事
Tom, I'm fine.
好吗
Okay?
我准备好离开这儿了
I'm ready to leave this place.
那个
You know...
天呐  或许
God, maybe...
有些东西在日本没有
there will be some things that they won't have in Japan.
是吗
Yeah?
嗯  或许我该去趟商店
Yeah, maybe I should go to the store and just...
确保我们拿上
make sure that we have
需要的一切
everything we need.
当然  好主意
Yeah, of course. Good idea.
要我陪你去吗
You want me to go with you?
不用  我去
No, I'll go.
好
Okay.
我  莱恩·雷
"I, Ryan Ray,
泄露了麦克米伦实用网络的源代码
released the MacMillan Utility source code.
我是一人行事
I acted alone.
没人帮我  没人教唆我
No one helped me, and no one told me to do it.
我这么做是因为"安全"只是个传说
I did this because 'security' is a myth.
与你们所听到的不同  朋友们
Contrary to what you might have heard, my friends,
你们不安全
you are not safe.
安全是个故事
Safety is a story.
我们把它告诉孩子们
It's something we teach our children
好让他们夜晚能够入睡
so they can sleep at night,
但我们知道那不是真的
but we know it's not real.
小心  困惑的人类
Beware, baffled humans.
小心向你兜售假未来的伪先知
Beware of false prophets who will sell you a fake future,
小心坏老师  腐败的领袖
of bad teachers, corrupt leaders
和肮脏的公司
and dirty corporations.
小心警察  抢劫犯
Beware of cops and robbers...
抢走你的梦想的抢劫犯
the kind that rob your dreams.
但最重要的
But most of all,
小心彼此
beware of each other,
因为一切都将改变
because everything's about to change.
世界会碎裂开来
The world is going to crack wide open.
有东西即将到来
There's something on the horizon.
广泛的连接
A massive connectivity.
我们之间的屏障将消失
The barriers between us will disappear,
我们还没准备好
and we're not ready.
我们将以新的方式伤害彼此
We'll hurt each other in new ways.
我们将出售  被卖
We'll sell and be sold.
我们将暴露最温柔的自己
We'll expose our most tender selves,
但只会被嘲笑  毁灭
only to be mocked and destroyed.
我们将如此脆弱
We'll be so vulnerable,
并为此付出代价
and we'll pay the price.
我们将无法假装
We won't be able to pretend
我们还能保护自己
that we can protect ourselves anymore.
这很危险
It's a huge danger,
很冒险
a gigantic risk,
但是值得的
but it's worth it.
如果我们能学会照顾彼此就好
If only we can learn to take care of each other.
那么这了不起的  毁灭性的新连接
Then this awesome, destructive new connection
将不会隔离我们
won't isolate us.
不会最终让我们
It won't leave us in the end so...
完全孤独
totally alone.